## **Ronnie Cheung**

Toronto, ON • (647) 828-3666 ronniech@outlook.com

## **Summary**

I am a front end web developer with over five years of professional experience developing and maintaining responsive web applications using the latest front end technologies. My educational and professional background, which has included subjects such as back end development, business analysis and UX design, has provided me a broad pool of knowledge that I have been able to draw upon to provide a unique perspective and approach to problem solving.

Portfolio: ronniecheung.ca

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ronniech

## **Professional Experience**

**Senior Web Developer**, Climax Media Inc., Toronto November 2015 to February 2019

- Acted as lead Front End developer on a wide variety of projects, utilizing many technologies and frameworks, including AngularJS, React and WordPress.
- Crafted detailed development approaches and provided thorough code reviews for team members to ensure clear technical objectives and expectations were met.
- Promoted to senior position within a year due to strong demonstrated problem solving, learning and analytical abilities.

**.NET Developer**, One Advertising (now Sandbox Advertising), Toronto September 2013 to November 2015

- Developed, updated and maintained numerous websites and web applications using a variety of programming languages and web technologies (including PHP).
- Seamlessly took over front end development responsibilities when called upon, demonstrating proficiency with responsive web design and modern front end frameworks.

**Project Coordinator (Internship)**, Research In Motion (now Blackberry), Waterloo January to April 2012

 Demonstrated C# web development and programming expertise in developing a secure, modular dashboard reporting web application designed to be used by several departments for separate purposes.

# **Business Analyst (Internship)**, CIBC, Toronto September to December 2011

• Exhibited strong work prioritization and multi-tasking skills required to work with multiple managers with different functions.

### **Ronnie Cheung**

# **Assistant Performance Analyst (Internship)**, Hydro One, Toronto January to April 2011

• Engineered a Java-based web service to access and manipulate an Oracle database using a combination of SQL and JDBC to facilitate dynamic data collection.

#### **Junior Technical Consultant (Internship)**, Innovapost, Mississauga September to December 2010

 Demonstrated object-oriented language expertise, using C#, ASP.NET and Visual Studio to create, test and modify web-based internal tools and applications.

### **Education**

Bachelor of Administrative Studies with Honours in Information Technology (Business Systems Analysis), York University, Toronto May 2007 to April 2013

## **Technical Skills**

#### Front End Languages and Technologies

Javascript (React, AngularJS, Ember.js, jQuery, vanilla), Webpack, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, Grunt, Gulp

#### **Back End Languages and Technologies**

C# (ASP.NET), PHP (Laravel, WordPress), SQL (Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle DBMS)

#### **Other Technologies**

Github, SVN, TeamCity, Microsoft Excel